Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit, I am the founder
of Family First Financial Services, I am an MBA Finance and have been working in the corporate sector for 14 years
and today I am presenting to you Bajaj Alias ​​Life Insurance,
after the changes that have come in the insurance industry after October 1, 2024, they
have launched a new term plan, eTouch 2. Earlier, they had eTouch plan, they
have updated it a bit, what is the update, I
will explain it to you in detail in this video, if you want to watch the video of eTouch, then I
will give you the link of that also in the last 20 seconds of the video, from where you can also watch the video of eTouch and eTouch 2,
I am going to explain in detail here, if you like the video, then definitely subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS,
where you will find around 300 insurance
related videos which
will help you in your financial planning, term insurance planning, savings and investment planning, thank you so much,
now this eTouch 2 has come It has mostly the same features as in eTouch.
I will explain the new features in the beginning so that it is easy for you. First of all,
they have come up with a rider called Family Protect Rider which is
called Parental Care. This rider is the first such company in the insurance industry and the first such plan
in which this rider is available which is not available in any other term plan in the industry till the age of
now 2024. In future, other companies may also come up with
such a rider. Now what is this Family Protect Rider or Parental Care Rider
actually? What is there in all the term plans that you have seen till now,
suppose there is a husband, suppose he is 30 years old, has a wife or children, he purchases the policy,
mostly the wife or children are kept as nominee, if he dies, then the wife
or children get the money and life goes on smoothly. The company has taken this rider
keeping the parents in mind, suppose many times,
suppose there is a single boy right now. Till now he is not married, he has started earning,
he is 25-30 years old and now if that boy dies,
what will happen to his parents, they have now reached the age of retirement, their earning has stopped,
how will their income keep coming or suppose you got the lump sum money of the term plan at one time, suppose
he was married, then the wife got the money, what about the parents, how will they get income for lifetime,
so keeping that in mind, this rider has
been launched by Bajaj Ace Life Insurance in the Etouch Plan where suppose you can
add single parents i.e. father or both parents mother and father both in it where
the premium of this rider will be separate, you can take a separate sum for it, suppose
you took the sum sed of Parental Care Rider of Rs one crore and here the income will be from 0 per pvt to 0.5 per month,
suppose you took an insurance cover of Rs one crore, took the rider and if you
selected the option of income, then if there is death As far as the proposer is concerned, parents
will get Rs 10000 per month as long as they live. If both the parents are there, then till the first one
dies, the second one dies, they
will keep getting Rs 500 every month for life and if there is death, then the money that was to be received in lump sum will definitely be received. So
this is a unique rider. I will explain it to you with a benefit illustration.
Let us see. Now let us understand
the parental care rider and family protect rider in Bajaj Allianz Life Touch 2. Let us assume that
the person is 35 years old and he is taking a policy term of 35 years, that is, a policy term of up to 70 years.
He wants to pay the regular premium and is taking an insurance cover of Rs 1 crore,
in which his premium is coming to Rs 2105. He
will pay the annual premium. GST in this is 18% and he
is taking the option of life child and he would like to take Rs 1 crore in case of 100% death. There is an insurance cover of Rs 1 crore
in this, both father and mother have been added in the parents.
The father's age is 60 years and the mother's age is 55 years and a rider of Rs. 50 lakhs has been taken.
The amount of parental care rider taken is Rs. 50 lakhs and it has been taken for 35 years
and the monthly income option taken is Rs. 04, that means if we do Rs. 50 lakh * 04 then
we will get Rs. 0000 per month for which the annual premium will be
Rs . 846. Now one thing to remember is that if this 35 year old person dies,
then the family will immediately get Rs. 1 crore plus the parents will
get Rs. 00 per month. Now suppose many times death does not occur in an accident, but the person
becomes totally permanently disabled, so if a total permanent disability occurs after taking this plan rider,
then this Rs. 00 per month will start coming. It is fine for the parents.
And this insurance of 1 crore will continue, you will get 1 crore on death as well,
but even if there is total permanent disability in an accident, this rider
is useful even then and it is useful on death as well. Now, in this, the base premium
is 000. If you are a single rider, you get a discount of 5%. If you
are purchasing insurance for the first time, you also get a discount of 5%. And here your
15,429 with discount becomes 18204 with GST
and from the second year, because the discount will not be there in the second year, your
premium will be 2073. GST is currently at 18. Next month, maybe this GST will be reduced.
Secondly, on the term plan, the premium for our parental rider is 846. With GST,
it will cost 6898. Your total, including everything, for ₹ 772, you
will get this insurance cover of ₹ crore plus parental care of both parents of ₹ lakh. Here you
can see that after the first discount, your premium will come to ₹ Then in the second year, this death benefit of ₹ crore is coming
on which guarantee is written
because it is on regular basis, so you will not see any surrender value here
till 25 years and after that
you will definitely see special exit value here, this is how this rider works, which
is available only in Bajaj Allians plan in the industry, age of now
till November 2024, in future it can also come in other companies,
this policy has three variants, Life Child, Life Child Plus and Life Child
RO, if we talk about these three features, then death benefit will be available in all these three options,
you will get the benefit of terminal illness in all these three features,
accidental cover will be inbuilt, you are getting in Life Child Plus, the option of waiver of premium
is available in all three options and you will get the option of return of premium
in Live Child OOP, if we talk about the eligibility criteria of the policy, then
a person from 18 years to 65 years can purchase this policy, if
you choose the option of return of premium If you select this option, the minimum entry age will be 25 years and the maximum
will be 65 years. If you select the option of Pay Till 60, then the minimum and maximum
entry age will be 55 years. Talking about the policy term,
you can take policy coverage from 10 years to 99 years of age. Suppose your age is 35 and you
want to take cover till 99, you can take it. If you want to take cover till the age of 40, you can take it. If
you want to take cover till the age of 85, you can take it. If you want to take cover for a policy term of 40 years, you can take it. You
can also take the premium payment in between.
Options of 5 years, 6 years, 10, 12, 15, 20, Pay Till 60 are given. If you want to pay the regular premium, you can also get
the cover of accidental death benefit. In this, you can take accidental cover from ₹ 5 lakh to ₹ crore.
The benefit of terminal illness is from ₹ 50 lakh to ₹ 2 crore.
You can get insurance cover. If you
take an insurance cover of more than 2 crores , then you
will get the benefit of terminal illness only up to a maximum of 2 crores. Suppose you have taken a policy of 5 crores, if terminal illness is diagnosed, then
you will get ₹ 1 crore immediately and the remaining ₹ 1 crore will be given to you after death.
Let us talk about the maximum and minimum premium in the policy, that depends
on your sum of money. In this, we have given you options of yearly, annually, semi-annually, quarterly and
monthly modes. Life Shield Option: If we talk about death benefit here,
suppose you have taken an insurance cover of ₹ 1 crore, if there is death, then the entire ₹ 1
crore will be given to the nominee. If the nominee wants, he can take a lump sum of one crore at once.
He can take it between 10 per cent to 90 per cent and the rest can be taken as monthly income.
Suppose he said I want % sum, that is, 50 lakhs will be given immediately and
the remaining 50 lakhs The nominee will keep getting the money on a monthly basis for the next five years.
Talking about terminal benefit in the policy, terminal benefit is where
the medical practitioner gives it in writing. Plus, on behalf of Bajaj Life Insurance or
whichever company's policy you are taking, a medical practitioner
and a doctor give it in writing that this patient's customer will
die due to this disease within six months due to this problem. At that time, your
insurance is between Rs 50 lakh and Rs 2 crore. So,
you will get 100% of the entire money. You can get a good treatment while you are alive. If your insurance
is Rs 2 crore or above, suppose you have an insurance of Rs 1 crore, then you
will get Rs 2 crore immediately. After that, if death occurs, the remaining Rs 9 crore is given to the nominee.
Let's talk about waiver of premium on accidental and permanent disability and
If a person becomes disabled in an accident, then
the premium payment will be waived. Or if he gets a terminal illness and
the premium payment is due at that time, then the premium payment will be waived. Now let us understand
the life care option with the benefit illustration. Let us now understand
the plan with the benefit illustration. Bajaj Ellis Life Etouch Two. In which we are seeing the first option is
Live Child, where you will get the benefit of terminalness,
the benefit of early exit will be available. Accidental cover will not be available in it. Waiver of premium
will be available. If the option of return of maturity
is not available in it, I have taken parental care here, where
an annual premium of Rs 1727 will give a monthly income of Rs 50,000.
Here, let us see, there is a 35-year-old person named Anil Rajpat, he
pays premium for 10 years, he is taking a policy term of 50 years, this
insurance cover of Rs 1 crore will run till 85. And here the Live Child option has been taken,
insurance cover of Rs 1 crore. And they want to take 100% money in case of lump sum death. They
have taken parental care rider. Father's age is 68 and mother's age is 66. And they
have taken a rider of Rs 1 crore for 40 years. The rider's premium payment is for 10 years. Monthly income is 0.5,
which means Rs 0000 will come every month for which the premium
will be Rs 7278. Including GST and taxes, the premium will be Rs 66550. Here
you can see that it is 'one crore' which is guaranteed. Premium has to be paid for 10 years only.
Here the surrender value will be generated after the premium payment term, it
will not be generated before that. And after the age of 7 years, you will get special exit value for the next 5 years,
which means you can close the policy by taking the total amount paid.
So in this way option number one will work
. Now let's talk about option number two, Life Shield Plus. The options
given in Life Shield are same as it is death benefit, terminal illness benefit, waiver of premium benefit,
all three will be available in this policy but The fourth extra benefit you will get is that you
can take the cover of accidental death benefit, you can take accidental rider
with additional premium, you can take this between 5 lakh to 2 crore,
suppose you took normal cover of ₹ crore and accidental cover of 1 crore, now if
there is death in an accident, the family will get 2 crore, if there is natural death, 1
crore will be given, so you can take this rider in this policy, under this option you can
also add accidental cover benefit in your policy, let's talk about option number two
in option two which is called Live Child Plus, what extra you get in Live Child Plus,
accidental benefit, there is no accidental benefit in the first option, plus
the rest of the terminal advantage benefit, early exit benefit and the benefit of waiver of premium
will also be there in this, here I have taken parental care of 50000 instead of one crore, I have
taken 50 lakh, whose monthly income I have kept 4 instead of 5 And you
can add this rider in 930. For example, if the person is 35 years old and the policy term is 50 years,
the premium is paid for 10 years. Option number two is Life Shield Plus,
normal cover of 1 crore and accidental cover of 1 crore. That means, if there is a natural death, 1
crore will be received. If there is death in an accident, 2 crore will be received. If there is no death in an accident
but the person becomes disabled, the parents will get 00 per month. If there is death
in an accident, then two crore will be received. Even after that, the parents will get 00 per month. As long as
both the mother and the father are alive, the life time insurance will keep coming. Its premium will be
9191. Same is written here guaranteed. The insurance cover of one crore is visible.
Here the surrender value is after 60 years of age. If you want,
you can also exit by taking 6 63121 in early exit.
Now we move towards the third option, which is called Life Child
Return. Of premium, the life options in this are all three, death
benefit, terminal benefit and waiver of premium, all three options are given
but accidental cover is not in this option. But there is a maturity benefit that if you
survive the entire policy year, then whatever money you have paid
will be refunded to you at the end of the policy term, suppose your premium was Rs. 0000, you had to
pay premium for 10 years, Rs. 5 lakh, you paid the premium, when your policy matures,
that is, suppose the policy is for 40 or 45 or 50 years, whichever you took, then if something happens to you, if you
die, then that is one year, you will get that, if it does not happen, then whatever
Rs. 5 lakh you have paid, you will get it refunded, which
is called life return of premium. What benefits will be there in return of premium that
Terminal insurance will be there but accidental cover will not be there, early exit option will also not
be there but the entire money paid will be refunded, waiver and premium benefits
will be available and here I will explain the rider that I have taken, I
am a 35 year old person, I am taking a policy term of 50 years, I am paying premium for 10 years, I
have taken the option of life child RP, I want to take 100% money at once, I
have taken natural cover of one crore, I will get the entire money paid on maturity
if I survive, that means I will get Rs. 75,6670, here in parental rider
I have taken single parents or I have taken only father, I have not taken mother,
father's age is 60 lakhs, cover is of 50 lakhs, I am taking it for 40 years, premium is paid for 10 years,
if I take it for Rs. 4,000 per month will be for father, till father lives
premium will be Rs. 8744, GST etc. in all together premium
will be Rs. 87,000 and I survived So here you
will see the column of maturity benefit here, that means you will get back the total money paid 756 670 If you
survive, then you can also see the surrender value anytime 7 56 So you
can see it from here, so if you want to surrender, then you can do it in between Now let's talk about
the early exit value benefit in this plan, which many people
also call zero cost plan or free of cost term insurance plan
What will happen in this plan is that when you turn 60, immediately after that for 5 years, you
can withdraw your total paid money excluding GST This is called
early exit or free of cost or zero cost term insurance plan, that means
you can withdraw the entire paid money anytime when you turn 60
Within the next 5 years what happens in the first stage benefit is that as the events of your life
keep happening, you also get the option to increase the insurance cover, suppose
your If you are married, you can increase your insurance cover up to a maximum of Rs 50 lakh. You
can increase it up to Rs 25 lakh on the birth of the first child
and Rs 25 lakh on the birth of the second child. If you are taking a home loan for your child's education, then also you
can increase the insurance cover up to Rs 25 lakh. Rs 25 lakh for a home loan and Rs 50 lakh
for an education loan. You will get the facility to increase the insurance cover up to Rs 25 lakh.
This is called upgrading your insurance with the life stage. Let's talk about
an excellent option called Premium Holiday. If you
have taken a premium payment term and policy term of more than 20 years, then you will get this option.
What was in this option? Now you must have seen that during the time of Covid, many people had
financial problems that they were not able to pay the premium. So here
you get these options three times that even if you do not pay the premium, your policy
will continue, suppose your premium was due and you took a premium holiday,
at that time also your insurance cover will continue, even if you die in that term Suppose
the insurance cover was one crore, then the entire one crore would go to the nominee. So,
at the time of inception, when you purchase the policy, you can select whether you
want this option or not. You can exercise this option only after a minimum of 5 years.
If you have taken this option once, then if you want to take this option the second time, you will
have to wait for 5 years. Let's talk about the death benefit payment option in the policy.
You can take the death benefit as a lump sum at one go and you
can take a lump sum from Rs. 10 per cent to Rs. 90 per cent and you can take the rest as monthly income. I have
explained all these things to you in detail in the benefit illustration as well. You will also
get a rebate in the plan, that is, you will get a discount as well. If you
are already buying Bajaj's, that means you are purchasing insurance for the first time, before this
you have not taken any life insurance plan from any company and you are taking this policy,
then you will get a discount of Rs. 5 if you are a salaried person, if you If you are salaried
then you will get a discount of 5% and if you are a staff, if you
are already an employee of Bajaj, then you will get a discount of 4%. Talking about other benefits and features of the policy,
you will not
get the surrender benefit in regular pay, you will get the benefit of surrender in limited pay, that too
after completion of the premium payment term. I have already explained this to you in the benefit illustration.
If you select the option of policy return of premium, then surrender benefit
gets generated from the second year. Talking about the grace period, it
has a grace period of 30 days and if you are taking the policy in monthly mode, then you will get a grace period of 15 days.
You get the benefit of grace period. You
get tax benefit in ATC at the rate of income tax and that benefit will be tax free. You will get free prepayment. The policy
will have a 15-day prepayment. If you want to cancel the policy for any reason, you
can cancel it and get the full amount back. No loan is available in the policy.
The revival period is of 5 years. If for any reason you are unable to pay the premium or
are unable to pay for two-three years, you
can revive the policy by paying the premium for two-three years at a time. You can continue it. Finally, if I summarize it
, Bajaj Ace Life Insurance's Etouch Two is a good term insurance plan. It
is an inexpensive term plan. Accidental rider is also given to you according to your needs.
There is also the benefit of terminal illness. There is also the option of return of premium. There
is also the option of early exit. You can also increase the insurance cover at the life stage and the most
unique thing is that parental care rider is also given in the life insurance industry
. Here parents will keep getting lifetime monthly income in your asset, so
in this sense it is an excellent product and if you see the comparison to premium then it
is also very good, plus if you are a sale rider then you are getting discount, if you
are buying insurance for the first time then you are getting discount, so discounts
are also available in this plan, if you liked the video then
do subscribe to my youtube2 Triple FS where you
will get around 300 videos related to insurance which will
help you in your financial planning or in purchasing insurance or term plan or saving plan
and if you want to purchase this plan from me or want to buy after consulting and comparing
then you can call me on 0940 3412, Jai Hind